{
  "fill_in_the_blank": [
    {
      "id": "f001",
      "question": "Mary doesn't get along (    ) the other classmates.",
      "choices": ["on", "as", "with", "into"],
      "answer": "with",
      "source_id": 31
    },
    {
      "id": "f002",
      "question": "Kate and I met (    ) the way to school.",
      "choices": ["on", "in", "by", "to"],
      "answer": "on",
      "source_id": 31
    },
    {
      "id": "f003",
      "question": "How long did you swim today? (    ) two hours.",
      "choices": ["Since", "For", "Through", "During"],
      "answer": "For",
      "source_id": 31
    },
    {
      "id": "f004",
      "question": "Come here (    ) once and help me, Tom.",
      "choices": ["at", "in", "with", "on"],
      "answer": "at",
      "source_id": 31
    },
    {
      "id": "f005",
      "question": "I'm tired. Let's take a (    ).",
      "choices": ["rest", "walk", "chance", "look"],
      "answer": "rest",
      "source_id": 31
    },
    {
      "id": "f006",
      "question": "Mike (    ) 200 meters in P.E. class yesterday",
      "choices": ["run", "ran", "running", "to run"],
      "answer": "ran",
      "source_id": 31
    },
    {
      "id": "f007",
      "question": "(    ) I get some water?",
      "choices": ["Have", "Could", "Am", "Would"],
      "answer": "Could",
      "source_id": 31
    },
    {
      "id": "f008",
      "question": "My aunt became a cook because she likes (    ).",
      "choices": ["cook", "cooks", "cooking", "cooked"],
      "answer": "cooking",
      "source_id": 31
    },
    {
      "id": "f009",
      "question": "What kind (    ) cake do you like?",
      "choices": ["as", "at", "to", "of"],
      "answer": "of",
      "source_id": 31
    },
    {
      "id": "f010",
      "question": "Meg made lunch for (    ).",
      "choices": ["him", "his", "he", "they"],
      "answer": "him",
      "source_id": 31
    },
    {
      "id": "f011",
      "question": "Bill looks (    ) a popular actor.",
      "choices": ["about", "on", "to", "like"],
      "answer": "like",
      "source_id": 31
    },
    {
      "id": "f012",
      "question": "I'm going (    ) her at nine tomorrow morning.",
      "choices": ["visiting", "visited", "visits", "to visit"],
      "answer": "to visit",
      "source_id": 31
    },
    {
      "id": "f013",
      "question": "More (    ) more people go to Japan recently.",
      "choices": ["and", "or", "but", "to"],
      "answer": "and",
      "source_id": 33
    },
    {
      "id": "f014",
      "question": "Are you (    ) for lunch?",
      "choices": ["easy", "early", "dirty", "ready"],
      "answer": "ready",
      "source_id": 33
    },
    {
      "id": "f015",
      "question": "We need to talk with each (    ).",
      "choices": ["about", "another", "much", "other"],
      "answer": "other",
      "source_id": 33
    },
    {
      "id": "f016",
      "question": "My room has a lot of pictures (    ) the wall.",
      "choices": ["in", "on", "over", "behind"],
      "answer": "on",
      "source_id": 33
    },
    {
      "id": "f017",
      "question": "A: Would you like (    ) piece of bread, Sam? B: No, thanks. I'm full.",
      "choices": ["another", "same", "few", "all"],
      "answer": "another",
      "source_id": 33
    },
    {
      "id": "f018",
      "question": "I'm waiting for her to (    ) her homework.",
      "choices": ["decide", "finish", "save", "invite"],
      "answer": "finish",
      "source_id": 33
    },
    {
      "id": "f019",
      "question": "(    ) we go to Meg's party tonight? -Yes, let's.",
      "choices": ["Would", "Shall", "May", "Must"],
      "answer": "Shall",
      "source_id": 33
    },
    {
      "id": "f020",
      "question": "Be (    ). It's still too hot to eat.",
      "choices": ["dangerous", "delicious", "careful", "beautiful"],
      "answer": "careful",
      "source_id": 33
    },
    {
      "id": "f021",
      "question": "If you bring me some tomatoes, I'll make soup with (    ).",
      "choices": ["him", "it", "her", "them"],
      "answer": "them",
      "source_id": 33
    },
    {
      "id": "f022",
      "question": "My sister's phone is (    ) than mine.",
      "choices": ["to new", "new", "newer", "newest"],
      "answer": "newer",
      "source_id": 33
    },
    {
      "id": "f023",
      "question": "Do you have any (    ) about the field trip tomorrow?",
      "choices": ["temperature", "information", "adventure", "example"],
      "answer": "information",
      "source_id": 33
    },
    {
      "id": "f024",
      "question": "I'm looking forward to (    ) you sometime.",
      "choices": ["seeing", "see", "saw", "seen"],
      "answer": "seeing",
      "source_id": 33
    },
    {
      "id": "f025",
      "question": "I'm going to the store (    ) buy some groceries.",
      "choices": ["to", "for", "but", "and"],
      "answer": "to",
      "source_id": 36
    },
    {
      "id": "f026",
      "question": "(    ) umbrella did you borrow? Was it Tom's?",
      "choices": ["Where", "Who", "Which", "Whose"],
      "answer": "Whose",
      "source_id": 36
    },
    {
      "id": "f027",
      "question": "I'm going to (    ) my friends to my birthday party.",
      "choices": ["invent", "invite", "increase", "include"],
      "answer": "invite",
      "source_id": 36
    },
    {
      "id": "f028",
      "question": "I have (    ) my homework before dinner.",
      "choices": ["finish", "to finish", "finishing", "finished"],
      "answer": "to finish",
      "source_id": 36
    },
    {
      "id": "f029",
      "question": "Don't forget to (    ) the lights when you leave the room.",
      "choices": ["take off", "show off", "get off", "turn off"],
      "answer": "turn off",
      "source_id": 36
    },
    {
      "id": "f030",
      "question": "My cat likes to sleep (    ) the sun.",
      "choices": ["for", "about", "in", "on"],
      "answer": "in",
      "source_id": 36
    },
    {
      "id": "f031",
      "question": "Math is (    ) for me than English.",
      "choices": ["harder", "harding", "to hard", "hard"],
      "answer": "harder",
      "source_id": 36
    },
    {
      "id": "f032",
      "question": "She checked the (    ) of the water before taking a bath.",
      "choices": ["dangerous", "temperature", "environment", "texture"],
      "answer": "temperature",
      "source_id": 36
    },
    {
      "id": "f033",
      "question": "This is the (    ) pizza I've ever tasted.",
      "choices": ["better", "most", "best", "well"],
      "answer": "best",
      "source_id": 36
    },
    {
      "id": "f034",
      "question": "I was absent (    ) school yesterday because I was not feeling well.",
      "choices": ["from", "for", "by", "on"],
      "answer": "from",
      "source_id": 36
    },
    {
      "id": "f035",
      "question": "Can I have the (    ) sandwich as my friend is having?",
      "choices": ["different", "thirsty", "hungry", "same"],
      "answer": "same",
      "source_id": 36
    },
    {
      "id": "f036",
      "question": "The blue car is faster (    ) the red one.",
      "choices": ["because", "but", "than", "as"],
      "answer": "than",
      "source_id": 36
    },
    {
      "id": "f037",
      "question": "Don't forget to bring your (    ) to the ski trip.",
      "choices": ["gloves", "dish", "teeth", "umbrella"],
      "answer": "gloves",
      "source_id": 39
    },
    {
      "id": "f038",
      "question": "She (    ) learning to play the piano when she was seven years old.",
      "choices": ["got", "brought", "kept", "began"],
      "answer": "began",
      "source_id": 39
    },
    {
      "id": "f039",
      "question": "It's raining outside, so let's stay (    ) the house.",
      "choices": ["inside", "free", "away", "behind"],
      "answer": "inside",
      "source_id": 39
    },
    {
      "id": "f040",
      "question": "I can meet you (    ) on Saturday or Sunday.",
      "choices": ["neither", "either", "both", "just"],
      "answer": "either",
      "source_id": 39
    },
    {
      "id": "f041",
      "question": "Children (    ) quickly, and their clothes become too small.",
      "choices": ["borrow", "graduate", "forget", "grow"],
      "answer": "grow",
      "source_id": 39
    },
    {
      "id": "f042",
      "question": "Learning how to cook is a (    ) skill for life.",
      "choices": ["popular", "right", "useful", "easy"],
      "answer": "useful",
      "source_id": 39
    },
    {
      "id": "f043",
      "question": "He (    ) a map to show us the way to the park.",
      "choices": ["broke", "stole", "drew", "caught"],
      "answer": "drew",
      "source_id": 39
    },
    {
      "id": "f044",
      "question": "He had to (    ) his running pace because he got tired.",
      "choices": ["slow down", "give up", "go back", "wait for"],
      "answer": "slow down",
      "source_id": 39
    },
    {
      "id": "f045",
      "question": "We need to leave early to make sure we don't (    ) the train.",
      "choices": ["sleep", "miss", "take", "bring"],
      "answer": "miss",
      "source_id": 39
    },
    {
      "id": "f046",
      "question": "The blue car is (    ) than the red one.",
      "choices": ["fast", "fastest", "to fast", "faster"],
      "answer": "faster",
      "source_id": 39
    },
    {
      "id": "f047",
      "question": "While hiking in the mountains, we (    ) a beautiful waterfall.",
      "choices": ["discovered", "prepared", "swam", "said"],
      "answer": "discovered",
      "source_id": 39
    },
    {
      "id": "f048",
      "question": "My brother is getting (    ) at playing the piano with practice.",
      "choices": ["colder", "older", "better", "faster"],
      "answer": "better",
      "source_id": 39
    },
    {
      "id": "f049",
      "question": "I will (    ) the office at 5:30 PM today.",
      "choices": ["grow", "climb", "keep", "leave"],
      "answer": "leave",
      "source_id": 42
    },
    {
      "id": "f050",
      "question": "I have to wake up early tomorrow because I have an (    ) test.",
      "choices": ["important", "quiet", "strong", "thirsty"],
      "answer": "important",
      "source_id": 42
    },
    {
      "id": "f051",
      "question": "There are a lot (    ) interesting museums in this city.",
      "choices": ["in", "with", "for", "of"],
      "answer": "of",
      "source_id": 42
    },
    {
      "id": "f052",
      "question": "I thought I lost my keys, but they were (    ) in my bag.",
      "choices": ["too", "yet", "still", "else"],
      "answer": "still",
      "source_id": 42
    },
    {
      "id": "f053",
      "question": "I have (    ) money to buy a new bicycle.",
      "choices": ["same", "enough", "good", "still"],
      "answer": "enough",
      "source_id": 42
    },
    {
      "id": "f054",
      "question": "I enjoy outdoor activities, (    ) example, hiking, biking, and camping.",
      "choices": ["with", "for", "on", "to"],
      "answer": "for",
      "source_id": 42
    },
    {
      "id": "f055",
      "question": "Tim is the (    ) member of our soccer team, but he's very polite.",
      "choices": ["too young", "much younger", "youngest", "as young"],
      "answer": "youngest",
      "source_id": 42
    },
    {
      "id": "f056",
      "question": "It's important to be (    ) and tell the truth, even if it's difficult.",
      "choices": ["angry", "useful", "honest", "different"],
      "answer": "honest",
      "source_id": 42
    },
    {
      "id": "f057",
      "question": "I (    ) finish my homework before going to bed.",
      "choices": ["must", "have", "as", "shall"],
      "answer": "must",
      "source_id": 42
    },
    {
      "id": "f058",
      "question": "Be (    ) in the movie theater. The film is about to start.",
      "choices": ["careful", "angry", "poor", "quiet"],
      "answer": "quiet",
      "source_id": 42
    },
    {
      "id": "f059",
      "question": "My family is planning a (    ) to the beach next month.",
      "choices": ["vacation", "examination", "language", "headache"],
      "answer": "vacation",
      "source_id": 42
    },
    {
      "id": "f060",
      "question": "The (    ) with the famous actor was very interesting.",
      "choices": ["telephone", "interview", "information", "temperature"],
      "answer": "interview",
      "source_id": 42
    },
    {
      "id": "f061",
      "question": "She has (    ) to the dentist because her tooth hurts.",
      "choices": ["going", "to go", "went", "goes"],
      "answer": "to go",
      "source_id": 45
    },
    {
      "id": "f062",
      "question": "I don't want to be (    ) for the bus, so I always leave home early.",
      "choices": ["sure", "late", "careful", "free"],
      "answer": "late",
      "source_id": 45
    },
    {
      "id": "f063",
      "question": "She borrowed my umbrella because she forgot (    ) at home.",
      "choices": ["her", "she", "his", "hers"],
      "answer": "hers",
      "source_id": 45
    },
    {
      "id": "f064",
      "question": "She travels to the city (    ) bus to visit her grandparents.",
      "choices": ["by", "with", "on", "for"],
      "answer": "by",
      "source_id": 45
    },
    {
      "id": "f065",
      "question": "Sarah will (    ) from high school next year.",
      "choices": ["graduate", "discover", "remember", "prepare"],
      "answer": "graduate",
      "source_id": 45
    },
    {
      "id": "f066",
      "question": "Tom and Lisa like to help (    ) with their homework.",
      "choices": ["too much", "even though", "by heart", "each other"],
      "answer": "each other",
      "source_id": 45
    },
    {
      "id": "f067",
      "question": "If you have a toothache, you should see a (    ) as soon as possible.",
      "choices": ["bank", "village", "dentist", "restaurant"],
      "answer": "dentist",
      "source_id": 45
    },
    {
      "id": "f068",
      "question": "We promised to keep (    ) touch and meet up at least once a year.",
      "choices": ["in", "about", "by", "also"],
      "answer": "in",
      "source_id": 45
    },
    {
      "id": "f069",
      "question": "The elephant is (    ) than the lion in the zoo.",
      "choices": ["biggest", "much bigger", "too big", "big enough"],
      "answer": "much bigger",
      "source_id": 45
    },
    {
      "id": "f070",
      "question": "She borrowed a (    ) from the library to research for her school project.",
      "choices": ["nothing", "clothes", "magazine", "planet"],
      "answer": "magazine",
      "source_id": 45
    },
    {
      "id": "f071",
      "question": "After a long day at work, I like to (    ) on the sofa and watch TV.",
      "choices": ["hold", "rest", "die", "fail"],
      "answer": "rest",
      "source_id": 45
    },
    {
      "id": "f072",
      "question": "The math problems in the homework were quite (    ) for me to solve.",
      "choices": ["glad", "useful", "wrong", "easy"],
      "answer": "easy",
      "source_id": 45
    },
    {
      "id": "f073",
      "question": "My mother was cooking dinner (    ) my father and I were watching TV.",
      "choices": ["while", "through", "among", "once"],
      "answer": "while",
      "source_id": 48
    },
    {
      "id": "f074",
      "question": "Last weekend, I practiced playing the guitar to (    ) for the concert.",
      "choices": ["borrow", "climb", "prepare", "introduce"],
      "answer": "prepare",
      "source_id": 48
    },
    {
      "id": "f075",
      "question": "A: I watched the soccer match on TV last night. B: Oh, I missed it. Who (    ) the game?",
      "choices": ["win", "won", "winning", "wins"],
      "answer": "won",
      "source_id": 48
    },
    {
      "id": "f076",
      "question": "Yesterday, I (    ) my time drawing pictures because the weather was rainy",
      "choices": ["bought", "spent", "forgot", "left"],
      "answer": "spent",
      "source_id": 48
    },
    {
      "id": "f077",
      "question": "At the market, I found vegetables (    ) sale and bought some for dinner.",
      "choices": ["at", "in", "to", "on"],
      "answer": "on",
      "source_id": 48
    },
    {
      "id": "f078",
      "question": "In the photo, my little brother is standing (    ) our family with a big smile.",
      "choices": ["behind", "above", "across", "under"],
      "answer": "behind",
      "source_id": 48
    },
    {
      "id": "f079",
      "question": "During the card game, I told a (    ) about the cards in my hand",
      "choices": ["cold", "walk", "lie", "time"],
      "answer": "lie",
      "source_id": 48
    },
    {
      "id": "f080",
      "question": "I (    ) a call from my friend, and we talked for an hour about our plans.",
      "choices": ["saved", "received", "seemed", "entered"],
      "answer": "received",
      "source_id": 48
    },
    {
      "id": "f081",
      "question": "Yesterday, I went to the new (    ) in town and bought a novel.",
      "choices": ["bookstore", "dentist", "mountain", "factory"],
      "answer": "bookstore",
      "source_id": 48
    },
    {
      "id": "f082",
      "question": "My sister is taller than me, but I think I'm the (    ) runner in our family.",
      "choices": ["faster", "too fast", "fastest", "fasting"],
      "answer": "fastest",
      "source_id": 48
    },
    {
      "id": "f083",
      "question": "The weather is nice. (    ) we take a walk in the park?",
      "choices": ["Let's", "Don't", "Shall", "May"],
      "answer": "Shall",
      "source_id": 48
    },
    {
      "id": "f084",
      "question": "The city lights looked especially (    ) from the top of the hill at night.",
      "choices": ["heavy", "pretty", "quiet", "bright"],
      "answer": "pretty",
      "source_id": 48
    }
  ],
  "scramble": [
    {
      "id": "s001",
      "question": "水を飲むことは体に良いです。(is/water/good/drinking / for) your health.",
      "choices": [
        "Drinking water is good for your health.",
        "Is drinking water good for your health.",
        "Good for your health is drinking water.",
        "Water drinking is for your good health."
      ],
      "answer": "Drinking water is good for your health.",
      "source_id": 2
    },
    {
      "id": "s002",
      "question": "お茶をもう少しいかがですか? (more/like/ you / would/some / tea)?",
      "choices": [
        "Would you like some more tea?",
        "Would like you some more tea?",
        "You would like some more tea?",
        "Like you would some more tea?"
      ],
      "answer": "Would you like some more tea?",
      "source_id": 2
    },
    {
      "id": "s003",
      "question": "窓を開けましょうか? (I/open/ the / shall/window)?",
      "choices": [
        "Shall I open the window?",
        "I shall open the window?",
        "Open I shall the window?",
        "The window shall I open?"
      ],
      "answer": "Shall I open the window?",
      "source_id": 2
    },
    {
      "id": "s004",
      "question": "ビルは人気のある俳優に似ています。Bill (like/popular/a/looks / actor).",
      "choices": [
        "Bill looks like a popular actor.",
        "Bill like looks a popular actor.",
        "A popular actor looks like Bill.",
        "Bill looks a popular like actor."
      ],
      "answer": "Bill looks like a popular actor.",
      "source_id": 2
    },
    {
      "id": "s005",
      "question": "ジェシーは彼女の妹を探しています。Jessy (is/her/looking/ for / sister).",
      "choices": [
        "Jessy is looking for her sister.",
        "Jessy is for looking her sister.",
        "Her sister is looking for Jessy.",
        "Looking for her sister is Jessy."
      ],
      "answer": "Jessy is looking for her sister.",
      "source_id": 2
    },
    {
      "id": "s006",
      "question": "あなたの電話番号を教えてください。Please (phone / tell / your / me / number).",
      "choices": [
        "Please tell me your phone number.",
        "Please me tell your phone number.",
        "Tell me please your phone number.",
        "Please tell your me phone number."
      ],
      "answer": "Please tell me your phone number.",
      "source_id": 2
    },
    {
      "id": "s007",
      "question": "明日英語を勉強する予定です。(study/I/going/to/am/ English) tomorrow.",
      "choices": [
        "I am going to study English tomorrow.",
        "I am to going study English tomorrow.",
        "Tomorrow I am going study to English.",
        "English I am going to study tomorrow."
      ],
      "answer": "I am going to study English tomorrow.",
      "source_id": 2
    },
    {
      "id": "s008",
      "question": "リサはショッピングを楽しむために新宿に行きました。Lisa (to/Shinjuku/enjoy/to/went) shopping.",
      "choices": [
        "Lisa went to Shinjuku to enjoy shopping.",
        "Lisa went to enjoy to Shinjuku shopping.",
        "To enjoy shopping, to Shinjuku Lisa went.",
        "Lisa went to shopping to enjoy Shinjuku."
      ],
      "answer": "Lisa went to Shinjuku to enjoy shopping.",
      "source_id": 2
    },
    {
      "id": "s009",
      "question": "先生が授業を始めると生徒たちは話すのをやめた。(stopped/ the / when / students / talking) the teacher started the class.",
      "choices": [
        "The students stopped talking when the teacher started the class.",
        "When the teacher started the class, talking the students stopped.",
        "The students talking stopped when the teacher started the class.",
        "Stopped talking the students when the teacher started the class."
      ],
      "answer": "The students stopped talking when the teacher started the class.",
      "source_id": 2
    },
    {
      "id": "s010",
      "question": "トムは泳ぐのが得意ではない。Tom (not/swimming/at/good/ is).",
      "choices": [
        "Tom is not good at swimming.",
        "Tom is good at not swimming.",
        "Not swimming is good at Tom.",
        "Tom is at not good swimming."
      ],
      "answer": "Tom is not good at swimming.",
      "source_id": 2
    },
    {
      "id": "s011",
      "question": "あなたのコンピューター使ってもよろしいでしょうか? (your/may/I/use/computer), please?",
      "choices": [
        "May I use your computer, please?",
        "I may use your computer, please?",
        "Please may I use your computer?",
        "May use I your computer, please?"
      ],
      "answer": "May I use your computer, please?",
      "source_id": 6
    },
    {
      "id": "s012",
      "question": "母の誕生日にいくつかケーキを作りました。I (cakes / some / for / made) my mum's birthday.",
      "choices": [
        "I made some cakes for my mum's birthday.",
        "I some made cakes for my mum's birthday.",
        "For my mum's birthday, I some cakes made.",
        "I made for my mum's birthday some cakes."
      ],
      "answer": "I made some cakes for my mum's birthday.",
      "source_id": 6
    },
    {
      "id": "s013",
      "question": "クラスで一番背の高い女の子は誰ですか? (in/girl/is/who/ tallest / the) your class?",
      "choices": [
        "Who is the tallest girl in your class?",
        "Who the tallest girl is in your class?",
        "Is who the tallest girl in your class?",
        "The tallest girl in your class is who?"
      ],
      "answer": "Who is the tallest girl in your class?",
      "source_id": 6
    },
    {
      "id": "s014",
      "question": "何か飲みものはいかがでしょうか? (something / drink / to / like / you / would )?",
      "choices": [
        "Would you like something to drink?",
        "You would like something to drink?",
        "Like you would something to drink?",
        "Would you like to something drink?"
      ],
      "answer": "Would you like something to drink?",
      "source_id": 6
    },
    {
      "id": "s015",
      "question": "アンディは毎日夕飯のあと、犬の散歩にでかけます。Andy (a/for/dog/my/walk / takes / after) dinner everyday.",
      "choices": [
        "Andy takes my dog for a walk after dinner everyday.",
        "Andy takes for a walk my dog after dinner everyday.",
        "Everyday Andy for a walk takes my dog after dinner.",
        "Andy my dog takes for a walk after dinner everyday."
      ],
      "answer": "Andy takes my dog for a walk after dinner everyday.",
      "source_id": 6
    },
    {
      "id": "s016",
      "question": "アリス、週末に買い物に行きませんか? (shopping/can/go/we/ this) weekend, Alice?",
      "choices": [
        "Can we go shopping this weekend, Alice?",
        "We can go shopping this weekend, Alice?",
        "Go shopping can we this weekend, Alice?",
        "Can go we shopping this weekend, Alice?"
      ],
      "answer": "Can we go shopping this weekend, Alice?",
      "source_id": 6
    },
    {
      "id": "s017",
      "question": "私の兄はスペイン語とフランス語どちらも知っています。My brother (French / Spanish / both / and / knows).",
      "choices": [
        "My brother knows both Spanish and French.",
        "My brother knows Spanish both and French.",
        "Both Spanish and French my brother knows.",
        "My brother both knows Spanish and French."
      ],
      "answer": "My brother knows both Spanish and French.",
      "source_id": 6
    },
    {
      "id": "s018",
      "question": "その写真を見せてもらえますか? Can you (show/me/ the / to / picture)?",
      "choices": [
        "Can you show the picture to me?",
        "Can you show me to the picture?",
        "Show me the picture can you to?",
        "Can you the picture show to me?"
      ],
      "answer": "Can you show the picture to me?",
      "source_id": 6
    },
    {
      "id": "s019",
      "question": "ジャックは来年バスケットボールのチームに参加する予定です。Jack (part / the / will / take / in) basketball team next year.",
      "choices": [
        "Jack will take part in the basketball team next year.",
        "Jack will take in part the basketball team next year.",
        "Next year Jack will take the part in basketball team.",
        "Jack will part take in the basketball team next year."
      ],
      "answer": "Jack will take part in the basketball team next year.",
      "source_id": 6
    },
    {
      "id": "s020",
      "question": "この映画はあの映画よりおもしろい。This movie is (one / more / interesting / that / than).",
      "choices": [
        "This movie is more interesting than that one.",
        "This movie is interesting more than that one.",
        "More interesting is this movie than that one.",
        "This movie than that one is more interesting."
      ],
      "answer": "This movie is more interesting than that one.",
      "source_id": 6
    },
    {
      "id": "s021",
      "question": "病気のため今日は授業を休む予定だ。(class/from/ I'll / absent / be) today due to illness.",
      "choices": [
        "I'll be absent from class today due to illness.",
        "Absent from class I'll be today due to illness.",
        "I'll be from class absent today due to illness.",
        "Today I'll be absent from class due to illness."
      ],
      "answer": "I'll be absent from class today due to illness.",
      "source_id": 10
    },
    {
      "id": "s022",
      "question": "ベンはテニス部に入っていますか? (member / a / the tennis club / of / is / Ben)?",
      "choices": [
        "Is Ben a member of the tennis club?",
        "Ben is a member of the tennis club?",
        "A member of the tennis club is Ben?",
        "Is a member Ben of the tennis club?"
      ],
      "answer": "Is Ben a member of the tennis club?",
      "source_id": 10
    },
    {
      "id": "s023",
      "question": "昨日英語を勉強するために本を買いました。I (bought / English / to / the book / study) yesterday.",
      "choices": [
        "I bought the book to study English yesterday.",
        "I bought to study English the book yesterday.",
        "Yesterday I to study English bought the book.",
        "I the book bought to study English yesterday."
      ],
      "answer": "I bought the book to study English yesterday.",
      "source_id": 10
    },
    {
      "id": "s024",
      "question": "銀行は図書館と美術館の間にあります。The bank (the museum / is / and / the library / between ).",
      "choices": [
        "The bank is between the library and the museum.",
        "Between the library and the museum is the bank.",
        "The bank is the library and between the museum.",
        "The library is between the bank and the museum."
      ],
      "answer": "The bank is between the library and the museum.",
      "source_id": 10
    },
    {
      "id": "s025",
      "question": "直美はいつも部屋をきれいにしています。Naomi (always / her / keeps / clean / room).",
      "choices": [
        "Naomi always keeps her room clean.",
        "Naomi keeps always her room clean.",
        "Her room Naomi always keeps clean.",
        "Naomi always keeps clean her room."
      ],
      "answer": "Naomi always keeps her room clean.",
      "source_id": 10
    },
    {
      "id": "s026",
      "question": "もし暇なら買い物に行きましょう。Let's (go / are / you / shopping / free / if).",
      "choices": [
        "Let's go shopping if you are free.",
        "If you are free, go let's shopping.",
        "Let's go if you are shopping free.",
        "Go shopping let's if you are free."
      ],
      "answer": "Let's go shopping if you are free.",
      "source_id": 10
    },
    {
      "id": "s027",
      "question": "彼は日本対スペインのサッカーの試合を明日見に行く He's going to see (Japan / and /the soccer game / between / Spain) tomorrow.",
      "choices": [
        "He's going to see the soccer game between Japan and Spain tomorrow.",
        "He's going to see between Japan and Spain the soccer game tomorrow.",
        "Tomorrow he's going to see the soccer game and between Japan Spain.",
        "The soccer game between Japan and Spain he's going to see tomorrow."
      ],
      "answer": "He's going to see the soccer game between Japan and Spain tomorrow.",
      "source_id": 10
    },
    {
      "id": "s028",
      "question": "京都タワーは東京タワーより高くありません。Kyoto Tower (not/than/taller / Tokyo Tower / is).",
      "choices": [
        "Kyoto Tower is not taller than Tokyo Tower.",
        "Kyoto Tower is taller not than Tokyo Tower.",
        "Not taller is Kyoto Tower than Tokyo Tower.",
        "Than Tokyo Tower, Kyoto Tower is not taller."
      ],
      "answer": "Kyoto Tower is not taller than Tokyo Tower.",
      "source_id": 10
    },
    {
      "id": "s029",
      "question": "私が家に帰った時、母はテレビを見ていました。My mother (home / when / TV/ watching / was / I / came).",
      "choices": [
        "My mother was watching TV when I came home.",
        "When I came home, watching TV was my mother.",
        "My mother was when I came home watching TV.",
        "I came home when my mother was watching TV."
      ],
      "answer": "My mother was watching TV when I came home.",
      "source_id": 10
    },
    {
      "id": "s030",
      "question": "野菜を食べるのに良いお店を探しています。I'm (eat/a/to/looking/good/for/place) vegetables.",
      "choices": [
        "I'm looking for a good place to eat vegetables.",
        "I'm looking for to eat a good place vegetables.",
        "A good place to eat vegetables I'm looking for.",
        "I'm looking to for a good place eat vegetables."
      ],
      "answer": "I'm looking for a good place to eat vegetables.",
      "source_id": 10
    },
    {
      "id": "s031",
      "question": "ごめん、今宿題を終わらせなきゃいけないの。Sorry, (have /my/I/homework / finish / to) today.",
      "choices": [
        "Sorry, I have to finish my homework today.",
        "Sorry, I have finish to my homework today.",
        "Today I have to finish my homework, sorry.",
        "Sorry, my homework I have to finish today."
      ],
      "answer": "Sorry, I have to finish my homework today.",
      "source_id": 15
    },
    {
      "id": "s032",
      "question": "兄は私より年上です。(than / older / brother / my / is / me).",
      "choices": [
        "My brother is older than me.",
        "Older than me is my brother.",
        "My brother than me is older.",
        "Me is older than my brother."
      ],
      "answer": "My brother is older than me.",
      "source_id": 15
    },
    {
      "id": "s033",
      "question": "姉のために誕生日ケーキをつくる予定です。I (for/my/sister / will / a birthday cake / bake).",
      "choices": [
        "I will bake a birthday cake for my sister.",
        "I will bake for my sister a birthday cake.",
        "A birthday cake I will bake for my sister.",
        "For my sister, I will a birthday cake bake."
      ],
      "answer": "I will bake a birthday cake for my sister.",
      "source_id": 15
    },
    {
      "id": "s034",
      "question": "お母さん、今お店に行く必要があるの? Mum, do (to/ the / we / go / need) store now?",
      "choices": [
        "Mum, do we need to go to the store now?",
        "Mum, do we go to need the store now?",
        "Do we need to go to the store now, Mum?",
        "Mum, do need we to go to the store now?"
      ],
      "answer": "Mum, do we need to go to the store now?",
      "source_id": 15
    },
    {
      "id": "s035",
      "question": "ナオミは今朝、泳いでいました。Naomi (was/ the / in / morning / swimming).",
      "choices": [
        "Naomi was swimming in the morning.",
        "In the morning, swimming was Naomi.",
        "Naomi was in the morning swimming.",
        "Swimming in the morning was Naomi."
      ],
      "answer": "Naomi was swimming in the morning.",
      "source_id": 15
    },
    {
      "id": "s036",
      "question": "もっと野菜を食べるべきです。(vegetables / eat / should / more / we).",
      "choices": [
        "We should eat more vegetables.",
        "More vegetables we should eat.",
        "We should more eat vegetables.",
        "Eat more vegetables we should."
      ],
      "answer": "We should eat more vegetables.",
      "source_id": 15
    },
    {
      "id": "s037",
      "question": "彼は彼女の宿題を手伝える。(her/help/can/with/he/homework).",
      "choices": [
        "He can help with her homework.",
        "He can help her with homework.",
        "With her homework, he can help.",
        "He with her homework can help."
      ],
      "answer": "He can help her with homework.",
      "source_id": 15
    },
    {
      "id": "s038",
      "question": "ジェニーは去年東京の友達に会いました。Jenny (visited / last year / her friends / Tokyo / in).",
      "choices": [
        "Jenny visited her friends in Tokyo last year.",
        "Jenny visited in Tokyo her friends last year.",
        "Last year Jenny visited her friends in Tokyo.",
        "Jenny last year in Tokyo visited her friends."
      ],
      "answer": "Jenny visited her friends in Tokyo last year.",
      "source_id": 15
    },
    {
      "id": "s039",
      "question": "この試験は今年一番むずかしい。(difficult / this / the exam / is / most / the ) year.",
      "choices": [
        "The exam is the most difficult this year.",
        "This year the exam is the most difficult.",
        "The most difficult exam is this year.",
        "The exam this year is the most difficult."
      ],
      "answer": "The exam is the most difficult this year.",
      "source_id": 15
    },
    {
      "id": "s040",
      "question": "前の携帯よりこの新しい携帯の方が高い。The new phone (old / expensive / is / than / the / one / more).",
      "choices": [
        "The new phone is more expensive than the old one.",
        "The new phone is expensive more than the old one.",
        "More expensive than the old one is the new phone.",
        "The new phone than the old one is more expensive."
      ],
      "answer": "The new phone is more expensive than the old one.",
      "source_id": 15
    },
    {
      "id": "s041",
      "question": "先月2、3回公園に行きました。We went (the park / a / times / couple / to / of) last month.",
      "choices": [
        "We went to the park a couple of times last month.",
        "We went to a couple of times the park last month.",
        "Last month we went to the park a couple of times.",
        "A couple of times we went to the park last month."
      ],
      "answer": "We went to the park a couple of times last month.",
      "source_id": 19
    },
    {
      "id": "s042",
      "question": "この山はあの山より高い。The mountain (higher / that / than / one / is).",
      "choices": [
        "The mountain is higher than that one.",
        "Higher than that one is the mountain.",
        "The mountain than that one is higher.",
        "That one is higher than the mountain."
      ],
      "answer": "The mountain is higher than that one.",
      "source_id": 19
    },
    {
      "id": "s043",
      "question": "あなたは妹と仲が良いですか? Do you (along / sister/get/ your / with)?",
      "choices": [
        "Do you get along with your sister?",
        "Do you get with along your sister?",
        "Get along with your sister do you?",
        "With your sister do you get along?"
      ],
      "answer": "Do you get along with your sister?",
      "source_id": 19
    },
    {
      "id": "s044",
      "question": "昨日は今日よりもっと寒かった。(yesterday / was / than / today / colder / much).",
      "choices": [
        "Yesterday was much colder than today.",
        "Much colder than today was yesterday.",
        "Yesterday was colder much than today.",
        "Today was much colder than yesterday."
      ],
      "answer": "Yesterday was much colder than today.",
      "source_id": 19
    },
    {
      "id": "s045",
      "question": "彼らは博物館とギャラリーどちらも行きました。They (the museum / the art gallery / visited / and / both).",
      "choices": [
        "They visited both the museum and the art gallery.",
        "They visited the museum and both the art gallery.",
        "Both the museum and the art gallery they visited.",
        "They both visited the museum and the art gallery."
      ],
      "answer": "They visited both the museum and the art gallery.",
      "source_id": 19
    },
    {
      "id": "s046",
      "question": "彼女はお気に入りの映画を見ているとき、いつも微笑んでいる。She (when / smiles / she / always / sees) her favorite movie.",
      "choices": [
        "She always smiles when she sees her favorite movie.",
        "She smiles always when she sees her favorite movie.",
        "When she sees her favorite movie, she smiles always.",
        "Always she smiles when she sees her favorite movie."
      ],
      "answer": "She always smiles when she sees her favorite movie.",
      "source_id": 19
    },
    {
      "id": "s047",
      "question": "将来のためにお金を節約することは重要です。(to/money/important / it's / save) for the future.",
      "choices": [
        "It's important to save money for the future.",
        "To save money for the future is important.",
        "Important it's to save money for the future.",
        "It's to save money important for the future."
      ],
      "answer": "It's important to save money for the future.",
      "source_id": 19
    },
    {
      "id": "s048",
      "question": "このクラスで一番背が高い人はジョンです。(in/person/ is / the / class / my / tallest) John.",
      "choices": [
        "The tallest person in my class is John.",
        "John is the tallest person in my class.",
        "In my class the tallest person is John.",
        "The tallest person is John in my class."
      ],
      "answer": "The tallest person in my class is John.",
      "source_id": 19
    },
    {
      "id": "s049",
      "question": "公園に行く途中でカフェに立ち寄りました。We stopped at a café (way / the / to / on / the / park).",
      "choices": [
        "We stopped at a café on the way to the park.",
        "On the way to the park, we stopped at a café.",
        "We stopped on the way to the park at a café.",
        "At a café we stopped on the way to the park."
      ],
      "answer": "We stopped at a café on the way to the park.",
      "source_id": 19
    },
    {
      "id": "s050",
      "question": "彼女は昨日、新しい子犬を隣人に紹介しました。She (her / puppy/to/new/introduced) the neighbors yesterday.",
      "choices": [
        "She introduced her new puppy to the neighbors yesterday.",
        "She introduced to the neighbors her new puppy yesterday.",
        "Yesterday she introduced her new puppy to the neighbors.",
        "Her new puppy she introduced to the neighbors yesterday."
      ],
      "answer": "She introduced her new puppy to the neighbors yesterday.",
      "source_id": 19
    },
    {
      "id": "s051",
      "question": "お塩を取ってもらえますか? (the salt / could / me / pass / you), please?",
      "choices": [
        "Could you pass me the salt, please?",
        "Could you pass the salt to me, please?",
        "Please could you pass me the salt?",
        "You could pass me the salt, please?"
      ],
      "answer": "Could you pass me the salt, please?",
      "source_id": 22
    },
    {
      "id": "s052",
      "question": "妹と私は週末ボードゲームを楽しみます。My sister (playing/I/and/ enjoy / board games) on weekends.",
      "choices": [
        "My sister and I enjoy playing board games on weekends.",
        "I and my sister enjoy playing board games on weekends.",
        "On weekends, my sister and I enjoy playing board games.",
        "Playing board games enjoy my sister and I on weekends."
      ],
      "answer": "My sister and I enjoy playing board games on weekends.",
      "source_id": 22
    },
    {
      "id": "s053",
      "question": "本屋で新しい本を買ったので、とても読むのが楽しみです。I (at / a new book / the bookstore / bought), and I'm excited to read it.",
      "choices": [
        "I bought a new book at the bookstore, and I'm excited to read it.",
        "At the bookstore I bought a new book, and I'm excited to read it.",
        "I bought at the bookstore a new book, and I'm excited to read it.",
        "A new book I bought at the bookstore, and I'm excited to read it."
      ],
      "answer": "I bought a new book at the bookstore, and I'm excited to read it.",
      "source_id": 22
    },
    {
      "id": "s054",
      "question": "冬は、雪だるまを作ったり雪の中遊ぶのが好きです。In winter, I (in / the snow/play/ like / to) and make a snowman.",
      "choices": [
        "In winter, I like to play in the snow and make a snowman.",
        "I like to play in the snow and make a snowman in winter.",
        "In the snow I like to play and make a snowman in winter.",
        "To play in the snow and make a snowman I like in winter."
      ],
      "answer": "In winter, I like to play in the snow and make a snowman.",
      "source_id": 22
    },
    {
      "id": "s055",
      "question": "私たちは家の前で家族写真を撮りました。We (of / a family photo / front/in/took) our house.",
      "choices": [
        "We took a family photo in front of our house.",
        "In front of our house, we took a family photo.",
        "A family photo we took in front of our house.",
        "We took in front of our house a family photo."
      ],
      "answer": "We took a family photo in front of our house.",
      "source_id": 22
    },
    {
      "id": "s056",
      "question": "私は動物と自然の絵を書くことが好きです。I like (animals / draw / to / of / pictures) and nature.",
      "choices": [
        "I like to draw pictures of animals and nature.",
        "I like to draw animals and pictures of nature.",
        "To draw pictures of animals and nature I like.",
        "Pictures of animals and nature I like to draw."
      ],
      "answer": "I like to draw pictures of animals and nature.",
      "source_id": 22
    },
    {
      "id": "s057",
      "question": "3時だ、チームミーティングの時間だね It's 3 o'clock, and (for / time / it's / our / team meeting).",
      "choices": [
        "It's 3 o'clock, and it's time for our team meeting.",
        "It's 3 o'clock, and time for our team meeting it's.",
        "And it's time for our team meeting, it's 3 o'clock.",
        "For our team meeting it's time, and it's 3 o'clock."
      ],
      "answer": "It's 3 o'clock, and it's time for our team meeting.",
      "source_id": 22
    },
    {
      "id": "s058",
      "question": "あなたは辛いものが好きですか? (spicy food / a fan / you / are / of )?",
      "choices": [
        "Are you a fan of spicy food?",
        "You are a fan of spicy food?",
        "A fan of spicy food are you?",
        "Are a fan you of spicy food?"
      ],
      "answer": "Are you a fan of spicy food?",
      "source_id": 22
    },
    {
      "id": "s059",
      "question": "気分が悪かったので、昨日は学校を休みました。I (absent / was/I/school/ from) yesterday because I wasn't feeling well.",
      "choices": [
        "I was absent from school yesterday because I wasn't feeling well.",
        "Because I wasn't feeling well, I was absent from school yesterday.",
        "Yesterday I was absent from school because I wasn't feeling well.",
        "I was from school absent yesterday because I wasn't feeling well."
      ],
      "answer": "I was absent from school yesterday because I wasn't feeling well.",
      "source_id": 22
    },
    {
      "id": "s060",
      "question": "どんな本を読むのが好きですか? What (you/do/kind / books / of) like to read for fun?",
      "choices": [
        "What kind of books do you like to read for fun?",
        "What kind of books for fun do you like to read?",
        "For fun what kind of books do you like to read?",
        "Do you like to read what kind of books for fun?"
      ],
      "answer": "What kind of books do you like to read for fun?",
      "source_id": 22
    },
    {
      "id": "s061",
      "question": "今日は学校に遅れたくないよ。I don't (for / late / want / be / to) school today.",
      "choices": [
        "I don't want to be late for school today.",
        "I don't want to for be late school today.",
        "Today I don't want to be late for school.",
        "For school today I don't want to be late."
      ],
      "answer": "I don't want to be late for school today.",
      "source_id": 28
    },
    {
      "id": "s062",
      "question": "外国の切手を集めることが私の趣味の一つです。(collecting / of /one/ is/ my hobbies) stamps from different countries.",
      "choices": [
        "One of my hobbies is collecting stamps from different countries.",
        "Collecting stamps from different countries is one of my hobbies.",
        "Is one of my hobbies collecting stamps from different countries.",
        "One of collecting stamps is my hobbies from different countries."
      ],
      "answer": "One of my hobbies is collecting stamps from different countries.",
      "source_id": 28
    },
    {
      "id": "s063",
      "question": "夕飯に母が美味しいトマトソースでスパゲッティを作ってくれた。For dinner, (a tasty tomato sauce / with / spaghetti / made / my mom).",
      "choices": [
        "For dinner, my mom made spaghetti with a tasty tomato sauce.",
        "My mom made spaghetti with a tasty tomato sauce for dinner.",
        "For dinner, with a tasty tomato sauce my mom made spaghetti.",
        "Spaghetti with a tasty tomato sauce my mom made for dinner."
      ],
      "answer": "For dinner, my mom made spaghetti with a tasty tomato sauce.",
      "source_id": 28
    },
    {
      "id": "s064",
      "question": "私のプロジェクトを手伝ってくれたので、先生にサンキューカードをあげた。I (a thank-you card/I/gave / for / my teacher) helping me with my project.",
      "choices": [
        "I gave my teacher a thank-you card for helping me with my project.",
        "For helping me with my project, I gave my teacher a thank-you card.",
        "I gave a thank-you card to my teacher for helping me with my project.",
        "My teacher I gave a thank-you card for helping me with my project."
      ],
      "answer": "I gave my teacher a thank-you card for helping me with my project.",
      "source_id": 28
    },
    {
      "id": "s065",
      "question": "僕の新しい友人、アレックスを紹介するよ。I'd (you/introduce / to / like / to) my new friend, Alex.",
      "choices": [
        "I'd like to introduce you to my new friend, Alex.",
        "I'd like to introduce to you my new friend, Alex.",
        "To my new friend, Alex, I'd like to introduce you.",
        "I'd like you to introduce to my new friend, Alex."
      ],
      "answer": "I'd like to introduce you to my new friend, Alex.",
      "source_id": 28
    },
    {
      "id": "s066",
      "question": "今晩、私たちと一緒に映画に行かない? (going to / are / with / you / come) us to the movies this evening?",
      "choices": [
        "Are you going to come with us to the movies this evening?",
        "Are you going with us to come to the movies this evening?",
        "To the movies this evening, are you going to come with us?",
        "With us to the movies this evening are you going to come?"
      ],
      "answer": "Are you going to come with us to the movies this evening?",
      "source_id": 28
    },
    {
      "id": "s067",
      "question": "雨が降っていたので、ピクニックを中止しなくてはいけませんでした It was raining, so (our picnic / to / had / we / cancel).",
      "choices": [
        "It was raining, so we had to cancel our picnic.",
        "So we had to cancel our picnic, it was raining.",
        "We had to cancel our picnic, so it was raining.",
        "It was raining, we had so to cancel our picnic."
      ],
      "answer": "It was raining, so we had to cancel our picnic.",
      "source_id": 28
    },
    {
      "id": "s068",
      "question": "夕方は犬と近所を散歩しています。In the evening, I (around / take / with / a walk / my dog) the neighborhood.",
      "choices": [
        "In the evening, I take a walk with my dog around the neighborhood.",
        "I take a walk with my dog around the neighborhood in the evening.",
        "Around the neighborhood, I take a walk with my dog in the evening.",
        "In the evening, I take with my dog a walk around the neighborhood."
      ],
      "answer": "In the evening, I take a walk with my dog around the neighborhood.",
      "source_id": 28
    },
    {
      "id": "s069",
      "question": "バックを持ちましょうか? (for/I/that bag / shall / carry) you?",
      "choices": [
        "Shall I carry that bag for you?",
        "I shall carry that bag for you?",
        "For you shall I carry that bag?",
        "Carry that bag for you shall I?"
      ],
      "answer": "Shall I carry that bag for you?",
      "source_id": 28
    },
    {
      "id": "s070",
      "question": "青いドレスは赤いドレスより安い。(is / the red one / than / cheaper / the blue dress).",
      "choices": [
        "The blue dress is cheaper than the red one.",
        "Cheaper than the red one is the blue dress.",
        "The blue dress than the red one is cheaper.",
        "The red one is cheaper than the blue dress."
      ],
      "answer": "The blue dress is cheaper than the red one.",
      "source_id": 28
    }
  ],
  "vocabulary": [
    {
      "id": "v001",
      "question": "cry",
      "choices": ["泣く", "呼ぶ", "去る", "壊す"],
      "answer": "泣く",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v002",
      "question": "call",
      "choices": ["呼ぶ、電話する", "泣く", "去る", "壊す"],
      "answer": "呼ぶ、電話する",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v003",
      "question": "leave",
      "choices": ["去る、出発する", "泣く", "呼ぶ", "壊す"],
      "answer": "去る、出発する",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v004",
      "question": "break",
      "choices": ["壊す", "泣く", "呼ぶ", "去る"],
      "answer": "壊す",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v005",
      "question": "grow",
      "choices": ["育つ、育てる", "登る", "保つ", "死ぬ"],
      "answer": "育つ、育てる",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v006",
      "question": "climb",
      "choices": ["登る", "育つ、育てる", "保つ", "死ぬ"],
      "answer": "登る",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v007",
      "question": "look",
      "choices": ["~に見える", "育つ、育てる", "登る", "死ぬ"],
      "answer": "~に見える",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v008",
      "question": "keep",
      "choices": ["保つ", "育つ、育てる", "登る", "死ぬ"],
      "answer": "保つ",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v009",
      "question": "die",
      "choices": ["死ぬ", "育つ、育てる", "登る", "保つ"],
      "answer": "死ぬ",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v010",
      "question": "discover",
      "choices": ["発見する", "をみがく", "紹介する", "投げる"],
      "answer": "発見する",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v011",
      "question": "brush",
      "choices": ["をみがく", "発見する", "紹介する", "投げる"],
      "answer": "をみがく",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v012",
      "question": "introduce",
      "choices": ["紹介する", "発見する", "をみがく", "投げる"],
      "answer": "紹介する",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v013",
      "question": "throw",
      "choices": ["投げる", "発見する", "をみがく", "紹介する"],
      "answer": "投げる",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v014",
      "question": "answer",
      "choices": ["に答える", "急ぐ", "学ぶ", "貸す"],
      "answer": "に答える",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v015",
      "question": "hurry",
      "choices": ["急ぐ", "に答える", "学ぶ", "貸す"],
      "answer": "急ぐ",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v016",
      "question": "learn",
      "choices": ["学ぶ", "に答える", "急ぐ", "貸す"],
      "answer": "学ぶ",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v017",
      "question": "lend",
      "choices": ["貸す", "に答える", "急ぐ", "学ぶ"],
      "answer": "貸す",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v018",
      "question": "rent",
      "choices": ["借りる(有料)", "借りる(無料)", "訪ねる、質問する", "記録する"],
      "answer": "借りる(有料)",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v019",
      "question": "borrow",
      "choices": ["借りる(無料)", "借りる(有料)", "訪ねる、質問する", "記録する"],
      "answer": "借りる(無料)",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v020",
      "question": "ask",
      "choices": ["訪ねる、質問する", "借りる(有料)", "借りる(無料)", "記録する"],
      "answer": "訪ねる、質問する",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v021",
      "question": "record",
      "choices": ["記録する", "借りる(有料)", "借りる(無料)", "訪ねる、質問する"],
      "answer": "記録する",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v022",
      "question": "catch",
      "choices": ["捕まえる", "卒業する", "加わる", "なくす"],
      "answer": "捕まえる",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v023",
      "question": "graduate",
      "choices": ["卒業する", "捕まえる", "加わる", "なくす"],
      "answer": "卒業する",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v024",
      "question": "join",
      "choices": ["加わる", "捕まえる", "卒業する", "なくす"],
      "answer": "加わる",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v025",
      "question": "lose",
      "choices": ["なくす", "捕まえる", "卒業する", "加わる"],
      "answer": "なくす",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v026",
      "question": "feel",
      "choices": ["感じる", "考える", "飛ぶ", "滞在する"],
      "answer": "感じる",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v027",
      "question": "think",
      "choices": ["考える", "感じる", "飛ぶ", "滞在する"],
      "answer": "考える",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v028",
      "question": "fly",
      "choices": ["飛ぶ", "感じる", "考える", "滞在する"],
      "answer": "飛ぶ",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v029",
      "question": "stay",
      "choices": ["滞在する", "感じる", "考える", "飛ぶ"],
      "answer": "滞在する",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v030",
      "question": "visit",
      "choices": ["訪れる", "動く、引っ越す", "到着する", "送る"],
      "answer": "訪れる",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v031",
      "question": "move",
      "choices": ["動く、引っ越す", "訪れる", "到着する", "送る"],
      "answer": "動く、引っ越す",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v032",
      "question": "arrive",
      "choices": ["到着する", "訪れる", "動く、引っ越す", "送る"],
      "answer": "到着する",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v033",
      "question": "send",
      "choices": ["送る", "訪れる", "動く、引っ越す", "到着する"],
      "answer": "送る",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v034",
      "question": "shut",
      "choices": ["閉める", "送る", "到着する", "動く、引っ越す"],
      "answer": "閉める",
      "source_id": 178
    },
    {
      "id": "v035",
      "question": "short",
      "choices": ["短い", "美しい", "かわいい", "異なった"],
      "answer": "短い",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v036",
      "question": "beautiful",
      "choices": ["美しい", "短い", "かわいい", "異なった"],
      "answer": "美しい",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v037",
      "question": "pretty",
      "choices": ["かわいい", "短い", "美しい", "異なった"],
      "answer": "かわいい",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v038",
      "question": "cute",
      "choices": ["かわいい", "短い", "美しい", "異なった"],
      "answer": "かわいい",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v039",
      "question": "different",
      "choices": ["異なった", "短い", "美しい", "かわいい"],
      "answer": "異なった",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v040",
      "question": "same",
      "choices": ["同じ", "お金もちの", "貧しい", "空腹の"],
      "answer": "同じ",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v041",
      "question": "rich",
      "choices": ["お金もちの", "同じ", "貧しい", "空腹の"],
      "answer": "お金もちの",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v042",
      "question": "poor",
      "choices": ["貧しい", "同じ", "お金もちの", "空腹の"],
      "answer": "貧しい",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v043",
      "question": "hungry",
      "choices": ["空腹の", "同じ", "お金もちの", "貧しい"],
      "answer": "空腹の",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v044",
      "question": "full",
      "choices": ["いっぱいの", "役立つ", "正しい、右の", "左の"],
      "answer": "いっぱいの",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v045",
      "question": "useful",
      "choices": ["役立つ", "いっぱいの", "正しい、右の", "左の"],
      "answer": "役立つ",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v046",
      "question": "right",
      "choices": ["正しい、右の", "いっぱいの", "役立つ", "左の"],
      "answer": "正しい、右の",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v047",
      "question": "left",
      "choices": ["左の", "いっぱいの", "役立つ", "正しい、右の"],
      "answer": "左の",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v048",
      "question": "ready",
      "choices": ["準備のできた", "一生懸命、大変", "間違った", "注意深い"],
      "answer": "準備のできた",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v049",
      "question": "hard",
      "choices": ["一生懸命、大変", "準備のできた", "間違った", "注意深い"],
      "answer": "一生懸命、大変",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v050",
      "question": "wrong",
      "choices": ["間違った", "準備のできた", "一生懸命、大変", "注意深い"],
      "answer": "間違った",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v051",
      "question": "careful",
      "choices": ["注意深い", "準備のできた", "一生懸命、大変", "間違った"],
      "answer": "注意深い",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v052",
      "question": "quiet",
      "choices": ["静かな", "ほかの", "そのような", "通常の"],
      "answer": "静かな",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v053",
      "question": "other",
      "choices": ["ほかの", "静かな", "そのような", "通常の"],
      "answer": "ほかの",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v054",
      "question": "another",
      "choices": ["ほかの、もう一つの", "そのような", "通常の", "違った"],
      "answer": "ほかの、もう一つの",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v055",
      "question": "such",
      "choices": ["そのような", "ほかの、もう一つの", "通常の", "違った"],
      "answer": "そのような",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v056",
      "question": "usual",
      "choices": ["通常の", "ほかの、もう一つの", "そのような", "違った"],
      "answer": "通常の",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v057",
      "question": "loud",
      "choices": ["(声が)大きい", "過去の", "奇妙な", "中央の"],
      "answer": "(声が)大きい",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v058",
      "question": "past",
      "choices": ["過去の", "(声が)大きい", "奇妙な", "中央の"],
      "answer": "過去の",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v059",
      "question": "strange",
      "choices": ["奇妙な", "(声が)大きい", "過去の", "中央の"],
      "answer": "奇妙な",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v060",
      "question": "central",
      "choices": ["中央の", "(声が)大きい", "過去の", "奇妙な"],
      "answer": "中央の",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v061",
      "question": "better",
      "choices": ["もっと良い", "一番良い", "どちらかの一方の", "中央の"],
      "answer": "もっと良い",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v062",
      "question": "best",
      "choices": ["一番良い", "もっと良い", "どちらかの一方の", "中央の"],
      "answer": "一番良い",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v063",
      "question": "either",
      "choices": ["どちらかの一方の", "もっと良い", "一番良い", "中央の"],
      "answer": "どちらかの一方の",
      "source_id": 174
    },
    {
      "id": "v064",
      "question": "easy",
      "choices": ["かんたん", "難しい", "忙しい", "無料の、ひまな"],
      "answer": "かんたん",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v065",
      "question": "difficult",
      "choices": ["難しい", "かんたん", "忙しい", "無料の、ひまな"],
      "answer": "難しい",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v066",
      "question": "busy",
      "choices": ["忙しい", "かんたん", "難しい", "無料の、ひまな"],
      "answer": "忙しい",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v067",
      "question": "free",
      "choices": ["無料の、ひまな", "かんたん", "難しい", "忙しい"],
      "answer": "無料の、ひまな",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v068",
      "question": "thirsty",
      "choices": ["のどがかわいた", "人気のある", "有名な", "興味深い"],
      "answer": "のどがかわいた",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v069",
      "question": "popular",
      "choices": ["人気のある", "のどがかわいた", "有名な", "興味深い"],
      "answer": "人気のある",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v070",
      "question": "famous",
      "choices": ["有名な", "のどがかわいた", "人気のある", "興味深い"],
      "answer": "有名な",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v071",
      "question": "interesting",
      "choices": ["興味深い", "のどがかわいた", "人気のある", "有名な"],
      "answer": "興味深い",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v072",
      "question": "funny",
      "choices": ["面白い", "ワクワクする", "怒った", "きれいな"],
      "answer": "面白い",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v073",
      "question": "exciting",
      "choices": ["ワクワクする", "面白い", "怒った", "きれいな"],
      "answer": "ワクワクする",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v074",
      "question": "angry",
      "choices": ["怒った", "面白い", "ワクワクする", "きれいな"],
      "answer": "怒った",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v075",
      "question": "clean",
      "choices": ["きれいな", "面白い", "ワクワクする", "怒った"],
      "answer": "きれいな",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v076",
      "question": "dirty",
      "choices": ["汚い", "慎重に", "奇妙な", "うれしい"],
      "answer": "汚い",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v077",
      "question": "glad",
      "choices": ["うれしい", "汚い", "慎重に", "奇妙な"],
      "answer": "うれしい",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v078",
      "question": "delicious",
      "choices": ["おいしい", "疲れた", "危険な", "大好きな"],
      "answer": "おいしい",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v079",
      "question": "tired",
      "choices": ["疲れた", "おいしい", "危険な", "大好きな"],
      "answer": "疲れた",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v080",
      "question": "dangerous",
      "choices": ["危険な", "おいしい", "疲れた", "大好きな"],
      "answer": "危険な",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v081",
      "question": "favorite",
      "choices": ["大好きな", "おいしい", "疲れた", "危険な"],
      "answer": "大好きな",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v082",
      "question": "young",
      "choices": ["若い", "早い", "速い", "遅い"],
      "answer": "若い",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v083",
      "question": "early",
      "choices": ["早い", "若い", "速い", "遅い"],
      "answer": "早い",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v084",
      "question": "fast",
      "choices": ["速い", "若い", "早い", "遅い"],
      "answer": "速い",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v085",
      "question": "late",
      "choices": ["遅い", "若い", "早い", "速い"],
      "answer": "遅い",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v086",
      "question": "strong",
      "choices": ["強い", "弱い", "親切な", "楽しみ"],
      "answer": "強い",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v087",
      "question": "weak",
      "choices": ["弱い", "強い", "親切な", "楽しみ"],
      "answer": "弱い",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v088",
      "question": "kind",
      "choices": ["親切な", "強い", "弱い", "楽しみ"],
      "answer": "親切な",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v089",
      "question": "fun",
      "choices": ["楽しみ", "強い", "弱い", "親切な"],
      "answer": "楽しみ",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v090",
      "question": "boring",
      "choices": ["退屈な", "病気の", "楽しみ", "親切な"],
      "answer": "退屈な",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v091",
      "question": "sick",
      "choices": ["病気の", "退屈な", "楽しみ", "親切な"],
      "answer": "病気の",
      "source_id": 176
    },
    {
      "id": "v092",
      "question": "near",
      "choices": ["~の近くに", "離れて", "~の間で", "~なので"],
      "answer": "~の近くに",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v093",
      "question": "away",
      "choices": ["離れて", "~の近くに", "~の間で", "~なので"],
      "answer": "離れて",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v094",
      "question": "between",
      "choices": ["~の間で", "~の近くに", "離れて", "~なので"],
      "answer": "~の間で",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v095",
      "question": "because",
      "choices": ["~なので", "~の近くに", "離れて", "~の間で"],
      "answer": "~なので",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v096",
      "question": "behind",
      "choices": ["~の後ろに", "~の前に", "~のあたり", "~について、約~"],
      "answer": "~の後ろに",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v097",
      "question": "front",
      "choices": ["~の前に", "~の後ろに", "~のあたり", "~について、約~"],
      "answer": "~の前に",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v098",
      "question": "around",
      "choices": ["~のあたり", "~の後ろに", "~の前に", "~について、約~"],
      "answer": "~のあたり",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v099",
      "question": "about",
      "choices": ["~について、約~", "~の後ろに", "~の前に", "~のあたり"],
      "answer": "~について、約~",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v100",
      "question": "above",
      "choices": ["~の上に", "~として", "~も", "すぐ"],
      "answer": "~の上に",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v101",
      "question": "as",
      "choices": ["~として", "~の上に", "~も", "すぐ"],
      "answer": "~として",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v102",
      "question": "also",
      "choices": ["~も", "~の上に", "~として", "すぐ"],
      "answer": "~も",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v103",
      "question": "soon",
      "choices": ["すぐ", "~の上に", "~として", "~も"],
      "answer": "すぐ",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v104",
      "question": "together",
      "choices": ["いっしょに", "時々", "よく", "普段、普通"],
      "answer": "いっしょに",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v105",
      "question": "sometimes",
      "choices": ["時々", "いっしょに", "よく", "普段、普通"],
      "answer": "時々",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v106",
      "question": "often",
      "choices": ["よく", "いっしょに", "時々", "普段、普通"],
      "answer": "よく",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v107",
      "question": "usually",
      "choices": ["普段、普通", "いっしょに", "時々", "よく"],
      "answer": "普段、普通",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v108",
      "question": "always",
      "choices": ["いつも", "まだ", "~すぎる", "他に、他の"],
      "answer": "いつも",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v109",
      "question": "still",
      "choices": ["まだ", "いつも", "~すぎる", "他に、他の"],
      "answer": "まだ",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v110",
      "question": "too",
      "choices": ["~すぎる", "いつも", "まだ", "他に、他の"],
      "answer": "~すぎる",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v111",
      "question": "else",
      "choices": ["他に、他の", "いつも", "まだ", "~すぎる"],
      "answer": "他に、他の",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v112",
      "question": "just",
      "choices": ["ただ〜だけ、ちょうど", "もしかすると", "~する間", "~の時"],
      "answer": "ただ〜だけ、ちょうど",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v113",
      "question": "maybe",
      "choices": ["もしかすると", "ただ〜だけ、ちょうど", "~する間", "~の時"],
      "answer": "もしかすると",
      "source_id": 180
    },
    {
      "id": "v114",
      "question": "when",
      "choices": ["~の時", "ただ〜だけ、ちょうど", "もしかすると", "~する間"],
      "answer": "~の時",
      "source_id": 180
    }
  ]
}
